A Guide to the Stonewall Jackson Papers 1844-1915
Virginia Military Institute Archives
Archives, Preston Library, Virginia Military Institute
Stonewall Jackson Papers 1844-1915
Archives, Preston Library, Virginia Military Institute
MS 0102
The collection consists of approximately 500 items, filed in 6 manuscript boxes.
The Stonewall Jackson Papers consist primarily of Jackson's outgoing personal correspondence for the years 1844-1860. The collection also contains a relatively small number of Civil War era papers, as well as the papers of Mary Anna Morrison Jackson, his second wife, and papers of the Arnold family.
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The bulk of the papers in this collection was donated to the VMI Archives by the Lee-Jackson Foundation in 1989. A small number of items in the collection were donated by others.
Alternative Form
A significant part of this collection available is available in full-text format on the VMI Archives website at http://www.vmi.edu/archives.aspx?id=4931
Biographical/Historical Information
Chronology
1824 January 21 Thomas Jonathan Jackson was born at Clarksburg, [West] Virginia. Parents: Jonathan Jackson (1790-1826) an attorney, and Julia Beckwith Neale (1798-1831). They were married in September 1817 and had four children: Elizabeth (1819-1826); Warren (1821-1841); Thomas (1824-1863); and Laura Ann (1826-1911).
1826 March Jackson's sister Elizabeth (age 6) and his father died of typhoid fever. Julia Jackson gave birth to Laura the day after her husband died. Widowed at age 28, Julia was left with extensive debts and the family was impoverished.
1830 - 1841 Julia Jackson remarried. Her new husband, Blake Woodson, disliked his stepchildren and the family had financial difficulties. A short time after the marriage, Thomas and Laura were sent to live with Jackson relatives in Jackson' s Mill [West] Virginia; Warren was sent to Neale relatives. Julia Jackson died, as a result of childbirth complications, on Dec. 4, 1831. She left behind the three Jackson siblings and a newborn son (Thomas's half brother), William Wirt Woodson (1831-1875). Jackson and Laura spent the remaining years of childhood with their paternal uncles. Jackson's brother, Warren, died of tuberculosis in 1841.
1842 June - 1846 June Jackson attended the United States Military Academy at West Point. Jackson was not the first choice for his congressional district's appointment, but the top applicant withdrew from the academy after only one day. Jackson graduated in June 1846, standing 17th out of 59 graduates. Jackson began his U.S. Army career as a 2nd Lt., First Artillery Regiment.
1846 - 1851 United States Army officer. Served in the Mexican War, 1846-1848; stationed at Carlisle Barracks, PA; Ft. Hamilton, NY; Ft. Meade, FL.
1851 Accepted a job as Professor of Natural and Experimental Philosophy and Instructor of Tactics at the Virginia Military Institute, Lexington, VA. Jackson remained at VMI until the Civil War began in April 1861.
1853 - 1854 In August 1853 married Elinor Junkin (1825-1854), daughter of Dr. George Junkin (President of Washington College) and Julia Miller Junkin. Elinor (Ellie) died in childbirth on October 22, 1854. Their child, a son, was stillborn.
1856 Summer Jackson toured Europe, visiting Belgium, France, Germany, Switzerland, England and Scotland.
1857 July 16 Jackson married for the second time. His wife was Mary Anna Morrison (1831-1915), daughter of Robert Hall Morrison and Mary Graham Morrison. Mary Anna's family resided in North Carolina; her father was the retired President of Davidson College.
1858 April 30 Mary Anna gave birth to a daughter, Mary Graham. The baby died less than a month later, on May 25.
1859 November Jackson was one of the VMI officers who accompanied a contingent of VMI cadets to Harper's Ferry, where they stood guard at the execution of abolitionist John Brown.
1861 April 21 VMI Corps of Cadets was ordered to Richmond to serve as drillmasters for new army recruits. Jackson was placed in command of the cadets
1861 April 27 Gov. John Letcher ordered Col. Jackson to take command at Harper's Ferry, where he organized the troops that would soon comprise the famous " Stonewall Brigade" (2nd, 4th, 5th, 27th and 33rd Virginia Infantry Regiments; Rockbridge Artillery; all were from the Shenandoah Valley region of Virginia).
1861 July Promoted to Brigadier General. Battle of 1st Manassas, where he acquired the legendary nickname Stonewall. "Look, there stands Jackson like a stone wall."
1861 October Promoted to Major General. Placed in command of the Valley of Virginia (Shenandoah Valley)
1862 May - June Shenandoah Valley Campaign; victories at Front Royal, Winchester, Cross Keys and Port Republic. Following the successful campaign, Jackson was ordered to join Gen. Lee in the Peninsula (Eastern Virginia).
1862 June 15 - July 1 Seven Days Battles.
1862 June - September Battles of Cedar Mountain, Clark's Mt., 2nd Manassas (July 21), Antietam (September 17).
1862 October Lee reorganized his army into two corps. Jackson was promoted to Lt. General and given command of the new Second Corps. Jackson was now in charge of half of Lee's Army of Northern Virginia.
1862 November Jackson's daughter, Julia Laura, was born. She was the only Jackson child to survive infancy.
1862 December 13 Battle of Fredericksburg
1862 December - 1863 March In quarters at Moss Neck, 10 miles south of Fredericksburg. The estate was owned by the Corbin family, who offered their home as winter headquarters.
1863 May 1 Battle of Chancellorsville begins
1863 May 2, 9:00 p.m. While reconnoitering with members of his staff, Jackson was accidentally fired upon by his own troops. The 18th North Carolina Infantry Regiment was responsible for the "friendly fire" incident. Jackson was struck by three .57 caliber bullets. He was taken to a field hospital near the battlefield, where his left arm was amputated.
1863 May 4 Jackson was moved to a field hospital at the home of Thomas and Mary Chandler, near Guiney Station, approximately 30 miles from the battlefield.
1863 May 10 Jackson died at 3:15 p.m. His last words were "Let us cross over the river and rest under the shade of the trees."
1863 May 15 The funeral and burial was took place in Lexington, Virginia, Jackson's home during his years as a Professor at VMI.
Scope and Content Information
The collection consists primarily of the personal papers of Civil War General Thomas Jonathan "Stonewall" Jackson (b. 1824 d. 1863). The bulk of the letters date from the pre-Civil War period and concern professional, personal and domestic matters, including many in which Jackson writes about his religious faith, his concerns about health and diet, and his family. The collection provides insight into Jackson's personality and philosophy, and presents a portrait of the man as he was in the years before he gained national fame as a wartime military leader. A small percentage of the documents date from the Civil War period and are directly related to Jackson's Confederate Army service.
The collection includes ca. 160 items of Jackson's outgoing correspondence, 1844-1863, spanning his cadetship at West Point; his service in the United States Army (1846-1851) including his participation in the Mexican War; his years as a faculty member at the Virginia Military Institute (1851-1861); and his career in the Confederate States Army. The bulk of the correspondence is addressed to his sister, Laura Ann (Jackson) Arnold. Other correspondents include Margaret Junkin Preston, and CSA Generals Joseph E. Johnston and Daniel Harvey Hill. Other series include miscellaneous incoming correspondence; miscellaneous Civil War reports, orders and dispatches; and documents associated with Jackson.
In addition to Jackson's personal papers, the collection contains the allied papers of Jackson's second wife, Mary Anna (Morrison) Jackson (ca. 143 items); his daughter Julia Jackson Christian (ca. 10 items); and his sister Laura Ann Jackson Arnold (ca. 115 items).
Contents List
- Correspondence, outgoing 1844-1863
  All are original letters (ALS) written by Jackson unless noted otherwise.
  - Cadet, United States Military Academy at West Point, NY, 1844-1846
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at West Point, NY, 1844 September 8, fragment (Box-folder 1:1)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at West Point, NY, 1845 February 10, fragment (Box-folder 1:2)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at West Point, NY, 1845 August 2, fragment (Box-folder 1:3)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at West Point, NY, 1845 November 25, fragment (Box-folder 1:4)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at West Point, NY, 1846 April 23, fragment (Box-folder 1:5)
  - United States Army Career. Mexican War,1846-1848
    - Letter to James Jackson, written on board ship James L. Day,1846 September 22 (Box-folder 1:6)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Pt. Isabel, Texas, 1846 September 25 (Box-folder 1:7)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Veracruz, Mexico, 1847 March 30 (Box-folder 1:8)
    - Letter to Brig. General Thomas S. Jessup, written at Veracruz, Mexico, 1847 March 30 (Box-folder 1:9)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Jalapa, Mexico, 1847 April 22 (Box-folder 1:10)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Jalapa, Mexico, 1847 May 25 (Box-folder 1:11)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Mexico City, 1848 February 28 (Box-folder 1:12)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Mexico City, 1848 March 23 (Box-folder 1:13)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at National Palace, Mexico, 1848 April 10 (Box-folder 1:14)
    - Letter to General Jones, written at Mexico City, 1848 May 20 (Box-folder 1:15)
  - United States Army Career. Post-Mexican War,1848-1851
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Governor's Island, NY, 1848 August 26 (Box-folder 1:16)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Carlisle Barracks, PA, 1848 September 5 (Box-folder 1:17)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Fort Hamilton, NY, 1849 January 1 (Box-folder 1:18)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Fort Hamilton, NY, 1849 February 2 (Box-folder 1:19)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Fort Hamilton, NY, 1849 April 27 (Box-folder 1:20)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Fort Hamilton, NY, 1849 June 12 (Box-folder 1:21)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Fort Hamilton, NY, 1849 July 2 (Box-folder 1:22)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Fort Hamilton, NY, 1850 April 1 (Box-folder 1:23)
    - Letter to James Jackson, written at Fort Hamilton, NY, 1850 April 24 (Box-folder 1:24)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Plattsburgh, NY, 1850 May 10 (Box-folder 1:25)
    - Letter to S. Lansing, written at Fort Hamilton, NY, 1850 May 20 (Box-folder 1:26)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Fort Hamilton, NY, 1850 July 6 (Box-folder 1:27)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Fort Ontario, NY, 1850 August 10 (Box-folder 1:28)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at West Point, NY, 1850 September 3 (Box-folder 1:29)
    - Letter to Francis H. Smith, written at Ft. Meade, Florida, 1851 February 25 (Box-folder 1:30A)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Ft. Meade, Florida, 1851 April 2 (Box-folder 1:30B)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Ft. Meade, Florida, 1851 April 22 (Box-folder 1:31A)
    - Letter to Francis H. Smith, written at Ft. Meade, Florida, 1851 April 22 (Box-folder 1:31B)
  - Professor at Virginia Military Institute 1851-1861
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1851 August 20 (Box-folder 1:32)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1851 October 8 (Box-folder 1:33)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1852 January 16 (Box-folder 1:34)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1852 February 7 (Box-folder 1:35)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1852 February 21 (Box-folder 1:36)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1852 April 10 (Box-folder 1:37)
    - Letter to George P. Terrill, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1852 May 1 (Box-folder 1:38)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1852 May 14 (Box-folder 1:39)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1852 June 5 (Box-folder 1:40)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Rockbridge Alum Springs, Virginia, 1852 July 12 (Box-folder 1:41)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1852 September 7 (Box-folder 1:42)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1852 October 9 (Box-folder 1:43)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1852 October 25 (Box-folder 1:44)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1852 November 11 (Box-folder 1:45)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1852 December 11 (Box-folder 1:46)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1853 February 1 (Box-folder 1:47)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1853 April 1 (Box-folder 1:48)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1853 April 15 (Box-folder 1:49)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1853 June 6 (Box-folder 1:50)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Rockbridge Alum Springs, Virginia, 1853 August 3 (Box-folder 1:51)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1853 October 19 (Box-folder 1:52)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1853 November 30 (Box-folder 1:53)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1854 February 14 (Box-folder 1:54)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1854 March 3 (Box-folder 1:55)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1854 April 7 (Box-folder 1:56)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1854 April 11 (Box-folder 1:57)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1854 May (Box-folder 1:58)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1854 May 2 (Box-folder 1:59)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1854 June 12 (Box-folder 1:60)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1854 July 1 (Box-folder 1:61)
      Includes portion written by Elinor Junkin Jackson
    - From Elinor Junkin Jackson to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Healing Springs, Virginia, 1854 July 24 (Box-folder 1:62)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1854 November 14 (Box-folder 1:63)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1855 February 20 (Box-folder 1:64)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1855 March 20 (Box-folder 1:65)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1855 April 4 (Box-folder 1:66)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1855 June 1 (Box-folder 1:67)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1855 June 18 (Box-folder 1:68)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at "Uncle Alfred's", 1855 August 10 (Box-folder 1:69)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1855 September 3 (Box-folder 1:70)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1855 October (Box-folder 1:71)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1855 October 6 (Box-folder 1:72)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1855 November 3 (Box-folder 1:73)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1855 November 13 (Box-folder 1:74)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1855 November 3 (Box-folder 1:75)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1856 month and day unknown (Box-folder 1:76)
    - Letter to aunt, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1856 January 14 (Box-folder 1:77)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1856 February 18 (Box-folder 1:78)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1856 March 31 (Box-folder 1:79)
    - Letter to nephew, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1856 April (Box-folder 1:80)
    - Letter to nephew, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1856 April (Box-folder 1:80)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1856 May 12 (Box-folder 1:81)
    - Letter to aunt, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1856 May 19 (Box-folder 1:82)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1856 June 6 (Box-folder 1:83)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at New York City, 1856 July 7 (Box-folder 1:84)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at onboard ship Asia,1856 July 18 (Box-folder 1:85)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Naples, Italy, 1856 July 18 (Box-folder 1:86)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1856 October 25 (Box-folder 1:87)
    - Letter to aunt, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1856 October 27 (Box-folder 1:88)
    - Letter to nephew, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1856 December 1 (Box-folder 1:89)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1856 December 6 (Box-folder 1:90)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1857 February 26 (Box-folder 2:1)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1857 May (Box-folder 2:2)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Rockbridge Alum Springs, Virginia, 1857 August 11 (Box-folder 2:3)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1857 November 1 (Box-folder 2:4)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1857 December 19 (Box-folder 2:5)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1858 February 8 (Box-folder 2:6)
    - Letter to brother, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1858 May 1 (Box-folder 2:7)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1858 May 1 (Box-folder 2:8)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1858 May 22 (Box-folder 2:9)
    - Letter to niece, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1858 June 7 (Box-folder 2:10A)
    - Letter to John Lyle Campbell, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1858 June 7 (Box-folder 2:10B)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1858 June 19 (Box-folder 2:11)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at New York City, 1858 July 21 (Box-folder 2:12)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1858 October 23 (Box-folder 2:13)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1859 February 19 (Box-folder 2:14A)
    - Letter to J. Jaquelin Smith, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1859 April 11 (Box-folder 2:14B)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1859 May 9 (Box-folder 2:15)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at White Sulphur Springs, Virginia, 1859 August 13 (Box-folder 2:16)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1859 August 27 (Box-folder 2:17)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1859 September 13 (Box-folder 2:18)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1859 October 31 (Box-folder 2:19)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1859 December 12 (Box-folder 2:20)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1860, no month or day (Box-folder 2:21)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1860, January 28 (Box-folder 2:22)
    - Letter to niece, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1860, February 25 (Box-folder 2:23)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1860, April 16 (Box-folder 2:24)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1860, April 21 (Box-folder 2:25)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1860, May 1 (Box-folder 2:26)
    - Letter to niece, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1860, May 7 (Box-folder 2:27)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1860, June 4 (Box-folder 2:28)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1860, June 30 (Box-folder 2:29)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Northampton, Massachusetts, 1860, July 21 (Box-folder 2:30)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Northampton, Massachusetts, 1860, August 4 (Box-folder 2:31)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1860, September 3 (Box-folder 2:32)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1860, September 24 (Box-folder 2:33)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1860, December 1 (Box-folder 2:34)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1860, December 29 (Box-folder 2:35)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1861, February 23 (Box-folder 2:36)
    - Letter to Laura Jackson Arnold, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1861, April 6 (Box-folder 2:37)
    - Letter to niece, written at Lexington, Virginia, 1861, April 13 (Box-folder 2:38)
  - Civil War, 1861-1863
    - Letter to James Jackson, written at Harper's Ferry [West] Virginia, 1861 April 30 (Box-folder 2:39)
    - Letter to Francis H. Smith, written at Harper's Ferry [West] Virginia, 1861 May 5 (Box-folder 2:40A)
    - Letter to Gov. John Letcher, written at Harper's Ferry [West] Virginia, 1861 May 25 (Box-folder 2:40B)
    - To Major ?, written at ?, 1862 January 2 (Box-folder 2:41)
    - To Gen. Joseph Johnston, written at Unger's Store, HQ, Valley District, 1862 January 13 (Box-folder 2:42)
    - To Rev. Francis McFarland, written at Winchester, Virginia, 1862 February 11 (Box-folder 2:43)
    - To Gen. Joseph Johnston, written at Winchester, Virginia, 1862 February 18 (Box-folder 2:44)
    - To Gen. D. H. Hill, written at Winchester, Virginia, 1862 March 4 (Box-folder 2:45)
    - To Colonel ?, written at Winchester, Virginia, 1862 March 7 (Box-folder 2:46)
    - To Colonel Pendleton, written at near Mt. Jackson, Virginia, 1862 March 20 (Box-folder 2:47)
    - To Margaret Langhorne, written at HQ, Valley District, Virginia, 1862 April 16 (Box-folder 2:48A)
    - To Francis H. Smith, written at HQ, Valley District, Virginia, 1862 April 18 (Box-folder 2:48B)
    - To Francis H. Smith, written at HQ, Swift Run Gap, Virginia, 1862 April 28 (Box-folder 2:48C)
    - Col. Pendleton, to Francis H. Smith, written at HQ, Valley District, Virginia, 1862 May 3 (Box-folder 2:49A)
    - To Alexander R. Boteler, written at near Harrisonburg, Virginia, 1862 May 19 (Box-folder 2:49B)
    - To Francis H. Smith, written at HQ, Valley District, Virginia, 1862 May 29 (Box-folder 2:49C)
    - To Colonel ?, written at Port Republic, Virginia, 1862 June 6 (Box-folder 2:50)
    - To Robert E. Lee, written at Brown's Gap, Virginia, 1862 June 11 (Box-folder 2:51)
    - To Revd. William S. White, written at Gordonsville, Virginia, 1862 June 20 (Box-folder 2:52)
    - To Gen. D. H. Hill, written at White Oak Bridge, Virginia, 1862 July 10 (Box-folder 2:53)